‘We are what we eat’ – or so the saying goes.
常言道，“人如其食”。
From calorie-inducing meals to low-fat lunches, much of our health depends on what we eat.
从容易摄入过量卡路里的大餐，到低脂午餐，我们的健康很大程度上取决于日常饮食。
We know about the benefits of eating properly for our physical wellbeing, but food – and cooking it – is proving to be good for our mental wellbeing as well.
我们都清楚合理膳食对身体健康的益处，但事实证明，食物本身以及烹饪的过程，对心理健康同样大有裨益。
Some people are now advocating the therapeutic value of cooking food.
如今有人开始倡导烹饪所具有的治疗价值。
It’s not just about the end result but the experience someone goes through.
这种价值不只体现在最终的成品上，更蕴藏在烹饪的全过程之中。
Dr Mark Salter, a consultant psychiatrist, told the BBC: “Baking and cooking are good occupational therapies that help patients develop planning skills, short-term memory and social skills – all of which suffer in mental illness.”
高级顾问精神病学家马克·索尔特博士在接受BBC采访时表示：“烘焙和烹饪是极佳的职业疗法，能帮助患者培养规划能力、短时记忆力以及社交能力——而这些能力在患上精神疾病后都会受到损害。”
TV chef and author Nadiya Hussain agrees that cooking is great for helping our mind.
电视主厨兼作家娜迪亚·侯赛因也认同烹饪对改善心理状态有显著作用。
She loves to bake and became the champion of the TV show, The Great British Bake Off.
她热爱烘焙，还曾夺得电视节目《英国家庭烘焙大赛》的冠军。
She says that “Baking’s always been about therapy... It’s never really been about the cake.”
她表示：“烘焙从来都与疗愈相关……蛋糕本身从来都不是核心。”
And she thinks that baking is an important tool for our socialisation and mental health.
在她看来，烘焙是帮助人们实现社交、维护心理健康的重要方式。
Certainly, creating some delicious food has helped some of us get through the recent lockdown; it’s helped take our mind off things and given us something to do.
诚然，制作美味的食物帮助许多人熬过了此前的封锁期，它能帮我们转移注意力，也能让我们的生活有所寄托。
People have said that kneading dough to make bread, for example, has given them a sense of calm and control.
比如有人说，揉面团做面包的过程，能让他们获得内心的平静和一种掌控感。
Research has shown that doing creative tasks, like cooking, makes us feel happier.
研究表明，从事烹饪这类创造性活动，能让我们感到更愉悦。
Nicole Farmer, who studies how food impacts our biology, behaviour and mental health, told BBC online that “cooking represents the shared human experience of food, and nurturing people through food, so I think that’s where it incorporates opportunity for immediate positive emotions.”
研究食物对人体生理机能、行为举止以及心理健康影响的妮可·法默在接受BBC在线采访时表示：“烹饪象征着人类共通的饮食体验，也是通过食物去滋养他人的过程，我认为这正是它能带来即时积极情绪的原因所在。”
Of course, cooking can be a very sociable activity and sharing the end result, a rewarding experience.
当然，烹饪本身就是一项极具社交属性的活动，分享烹饪成果更是一种能带来成就感的体验。
Hopefully, as we start to mix with friends and family again, we can enjoy the benefits once more and put us all in the right frame of mind.
希望随着我们重新与亲友相聚，能再次享受烹饪带来的种种益处，让每个人都拥有良好的精神状态。